Guide to the George A. Romero Archival Collection, 1962-2017 SC.2019.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Production Materials, circa 1962-2008; II.
  - Produced Works, circa 1962-2008; 1.
    - Martin, 1975-1978; 7.
      - Film festival correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 54, Folder 10)
      - Martin [Blood] Budget Details (13 copies), March 10, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 11)
      - Martin [Blood] Budget Details (12 copies), March 17, 1975 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Dawn of the Dead, 1974-1998; 8.
      A sequel to Night of the Living Dead in which four people try to survive the zombie apocalypse inside of a mall. Shot in the Monroeville Mall in Monroeville, PA and surrounding areas. Starring David Emge, Ken Foree, Scott Reiniger, and Gaylen Ross. Written and directed by George A. Romero.
      - Letter to Richard about Dawn of the Dead with partial synopsis, April 9, 1974 (Box 54, Folder 13)
        Letter addressed to Richard (presumably producer Rubinstein) to type up in response to AIP meeting.
      - Dawn of the Dead screening report, January 24, 1979 (Box 54, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence about Dawn of the Dead dvd releases, 1997-1998 (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Knightriders, 1980-1981; 9.
      - Knightriders synopsis and fundraising booklet (3 copies), 1978 (Box 54, Folder 16)
      - Knightriders materials, 1980-1982 (Box 54, Folder 17)
        Partial shot list, letter about potential school screenings in New York.
    - Creepshow, 1980-1982; 10.
      A horror comedy anthology film adapting the tone and style of EC horror comics from the 1950s. Filmed in Pittsburgh, Monroeville, and surrounding areas. Starring Hal Holbrook, Adrienne Barbeau, Ted Danson, Leslie Nielson, Ed Harris, E.G. Marshall, and Stephen King. Written by Stephen King and directed by George A. Romero.
      - Creepshow synopses, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 18)
        Written by Stephen King. Includes versions in English, French, German, Italian, Japanese, and Spanish.
      - Creepshow shooting schedule and locations binder, November 24, 1980 (Box 54, Folder 19)
      - Creepshow production materials, 1980-1982 (Box 54, Folder 20)
        Production materials from Creepshow, specifically the segment "Father's Day". Includes revision pages, call and contact sheets, shooting location directions, notes, and artwork related to the segment. Includes revision pages for "The Crate" segment. Also includes articles and information on Stephen King; biographies of George A. Romero, Richard Rubinstein, and Tom Savini.
    - Day of the Dead, 1985; 11.
      - Day of the Dead production material, 1985 (Box 55, Folder 1)
        Materials largely from production binder. Includes shooting schedule, cast and crew lists, correspondence, production budget.
    - Tales from the Darkside TV Series, 1986; 12.
      - Pitch/synopsis for series, circa 1985-86 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      - Contract for "The Circus", February 10, 1986 (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence about "The Ginger Bread Witch", February 21, 1986 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Creepshow II, June 17, 1986; 13.
      - Letter from Mike Gornick about filming of wraparound sequences, June 17, 1986 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Monkey Shines, 1985-1989; 14.
      - Letter from Stephen King, February 12, 1987 (Box 55, Folder 6)
      - Monkey Shines budgets, 1987-1988 (Box 55, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence between Michael Stewart and Peter A. Greenwald, 1985-1989 (Box 55, Folder 8)
        Includes correspondence about Monkey Shines, as well as corresponence and materials for other unrealized projects.
      - Monkey Shines correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 55, Folder 9)
        Includes correspondence about production and reshoots, script revisions, puppet effects proposals. From production binder.
      - Monkey Shines contracts: personnel, 1987-1988 (Box 55, Folder 10)
        From production binder.
      - Monkey Shines memoranda, 1987-1988 (Box 55, Folder 11)
        Production documents and correspondence. From production binder.
      - Monkey Shines parties, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 1)
        Guest lists and other materials regarding parties for premieres. From production binder.
      - Monkey Shines notes, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 2)
        Notes regarding script revisions and personnel. From production binder.
      - Monkey Shines agreement, June 5, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 3)
        George A. Romero contract.
      - Monkey Shines correspondence, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Monkey Shines correspondence, 1986-2008 (Box 56, Folder 5)
        Includes contract.
      - Monkey Shines titles, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 6)
      - Monkey Shines script notes, 1985-1987 (Box 56, Folder 7)
      - Monkey Shines TV, Trailer, Print Campaigns materials, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 8)
      - Monkey Shines shooting script addenda, 1987 (Box 56, Folder 9)
      - "Signifyin' Monkey" Monkey Shines storyboard test/test shoot, February 27, 1987 (Box 57, Folder 1)
        Film of this also in collection, on 3/4" tape.
      - Monkey Shines notes for revision by Peter A. Grunwald, undated (Box 57, Folder 2)
        2 copies.
    - Night of the Living Dead [1990], 1986-1994; 15.
      - Night of the Living Dead production disputes, 1990 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      - Night of the Living Dead producer's agreement, 1990 (Box 57, Folder 4)
        Correspondence, materials, and contracts related to producer's agreement.
      - Night of the Living Dead production correspondences, 1986-1994 (Box 57, Folder 5)
        Includes correspondences, notes, contracts.
      - Night of the Living Dead history, 1990 (Box 57, Folder 6)
        History of copyright and legal ownership of Night of the Living Dead from 1968-1990.
      - Night of the Living Dead blocking diagrams, July 14, 1990 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Two Evil Eyes ["Edgar Allen Poe Project"], 1989; 16.
      - "Edgar Allen Poe Project" contract, January 6, 1989 (Box 57, Folder 8)
      - Two Evil Eyes contracts and correspondences, 1989 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - The Dark Half, 1989-1995; 17.
      - The Dark Half correspondence, April 20, 1995 (Box 57, Folder 10)
      - The Dark Half correspondence, 1990-1993 (Box 57, Folder 11)
        Includes correspondence and contracts.
      - The Dark Half correspondence and story notes, 1990-1991 (Box 57, Folder 12)
      - The Dark Half legal correspondence, 1990 (Box 57, Folder 13)
        Includes contracts and correspondence about contracts. From production binder.
      - The Dark Half contracts, 1989-1990 (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - The Dark Half financing binder, 1990 (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - The Dark Half music licensing agreement, 1991 (Box 58, Folder 3)
      - The Dark Half Julie Harris contracts, 1990-1991 (Box 58, Folder 4)
      - The Dark Half Royal Dano contract, October, 1990 (Box 58, Folder 5)
      - The Dark Half TV campaign, 1993 (Box 58, Folder 6)
      - The Dark Half radio campaign, 1993 (Box 58, Folder 7)
      - The Dark Half audience survey, June 11, 1991 (Box 58, Folder 8)
      - The Dark Half production materials, 1990-1991 (Box 59, Folder 1)
        Includes lists of personnel, cast, and one-line schedules.
      - The Dark Half shooting schedule, October 29, 1990 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Jacaranda Joe, 1993-1994; 18.
      - Jacaranda Joe materials, 1993-1994 (Box 59, Folder 3)
        Includes storyboards, personnel materials, script, correspondence, creature sketches.
    - Biohazard 2 commercial, 1997; 19.
      A Japanese commercial for the video game Biohazard 2 (a game that was released in the United States as Resident Evil 2), in which two characters from the video game attempt to survive attack from a horde of zombies. Filmed in Japan and broadcast only in Japan. Starring Brad Renfro and Adrienne Frantz. Make-up effects by Screaming Mad George. Directed by George A. Romero.
      - Biohazard 2 production materials, 1997 (Box 59, Folder 4)
        Includes "Orientation" folder with storyboards, character sketches, character descriptions. Also includes journalistic set account.
    - Bruiser, 1999-2000; 20.
      - Bruiser expenses, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Bruiser insurance, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - Bruiser Faceless LLC operating agreement, May 1999 (Box 59, Folder 7)
      - Bruiser intermediary agreement, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 8)
      - Bruiser loan agreement, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 9)
      - Bruiser Loeb & Loeb legal agreement, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 10)
      - Bruiser Natexia Banque loan agreement, 2000 (Box 59, Folder 11)
      - Bruiser option agreement, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 12)
      - Bruiser production schedules, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 13)
      - Bruiser producer agreement, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 14)
      - Bruiser production files, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 15)
      - Bruiser Cinema Completions International, Inc. agreements, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - Bruiser budget, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - Bruiser casting, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Bruiser Chase Bank request for funds, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Bruiser Republic Bank correspondence, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Bruiser research, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - Bruiser Studio Canal+, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 7)
      - Bruiser post agreements, 1999-2000 (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - Bruiser WGA correspondence, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Bruiser wrap notes, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Bruiser production files, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - Bruiser production files, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 12)
      - Bruiser copyright, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 13)
      - Bruiser DGA correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box 60, Folder 14)
      - Bruiser delivery items, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 15)
      - Bruiser director's agreement, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 16)
      - Bruiser actor contracts, 1999 (Box 60, Folder 17)
      - Bruiser call sheets, 1999 (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Bruiser personnel contact lists, 1999 (Box 61, Folder 2)
      - Bruiser cost report/daily production report, 1999 (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - Bruiser Day out of Days/insurance certificates/location agreements, 1999 (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - Bruiser schedules/synopsis/travel summary/union agreement, 1999 (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Bruiser production loan binder, 1999 (Box 61, Folder 6)
      - Bruiser production loan binder, 1999 (Box 61, Folder 7)
      - Bruiser production loan binder, 1999 (Box 62, Folder 1)
      - Bruiser production loan binder, 1999 (Box 62, Folder 2)
      - Bruiser production loan binder, 1999 (Box 62, Folder 3)
      - Bruiser Jason Flemyng contracts, 1999 (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - Bruiser financing & checks, 1999 (Box 62, Folder 5)
      - Bruiser concept artwork by Alina Panova, 1999 (Oversize 67, Folder 1)
    - Land of the Dead [Dead Reckoning], 2000-2008; 21.
      - Land of the Dead [Dead Reckoning] title registration bureau documentation, September 1, 2000 (Box 62, Folder 6)
      - Land of the Dead [Dead Reckoning] correspondence, memorandum, and production documents, 2002-2005 (Box 62, Folder 7)
        Various documents pertaining to production and development from binder belonging to executive producer Peter Grunwald.
      - Land of the Dead [Dead Reckoning] correspondence, memorandum, and production documents, 2002-2008 (Box 62, Folder 8)
        Various documents pertaining to production and development from file folder belonging to executive producer Peter Grunwald.
      - Land of the Dead first pass schedule and cast day-out-of-days, June 17, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Land of the Dead first pass budget and critical assumptions for Vancouver shoot, June 24, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Land of the Dead first pass budget and critical assumptions for Winnipeg shoot, June 28, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Land of the Dead critical assumptions for Pittsburgh shoot (copy 1), July 26, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Land of the Dead critical assumptions for Pittsburgh Shoot (copy 2), July 26, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Land of the Dead critical assumptions for Toronto shoot, July 26, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - Land of the Dead critical assumptions for Toronto shoot, July 29, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 7)
      - Land of the Dead visual CGI and VFX correspondence and notes, July - August 2004 (Box 63, Folder 8)
      - Land of the Dead SFX quotes, August - October 2004 (Box 63, Folder 9)
      - Dead Reckoning vehicle design sketches (2 copies), 2004 (Oversize 67, Folder 2)
      - Dead Reckoning vehicle design, set, and gun shop poster sketches (2 copies), 2004 (Oversize 67, Folder 3)
      - Dead Reckoning vehicle design drawings and blueprints (2 copies), August 23-27, 2004 (Oversize 67, Folder 4)
        Concept designs and blueprints for Dead Reckoning vehicle. Includes designs for exteriors, weapons and hatch, and interior gun stations. Drawings by Rob Ballantine.
      - Land of the Dead Union Bank of California loan officer's certificate, September 1, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 10)
      - Land of the Dead script notes, September 7, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 11)
        Romero's script notes based upon the August 24, 2004 draft script.
      - Land of the Dead union and guild agreements, 2002-2004 (Box 63, Folder 12)
      - Land of the Dead actor memos, correspondence, and contracts, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 13)
      - Land of the Dead crew memos, correspondence, and contracts, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 14)
      - Land of the Dead clearances, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 15)
      - Land of the Dead cast and crew contact lists, September 2004 - January 2005 (Box 63, Folder 16)
      - Land of the Dead prep schedules, September - October 2004 (Box 63, Folder 17)
      - Land of the Dead prop department weapons breakdowns, September 30 - October 1, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 18)
      - Land of the Dead costume designs for Chihuahua and Slack characters, 2004 (Oversize 67, Folder 5)
      - Dead Reckoning vehicle color renderings, 2004 (Oversize 67, Folder 6)
      - Dead Reckoning vehicle color test renderings (2 copies), 2004 (Oversize 67, Folder 7)
      - Land of the Dead budget estimates, October 1-2, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 19)
      - Land of the Dead final budget, October 12, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 20)
      - Land of the Dead scenes outline and notes, 2004 (Box 63, Folder 21)
      - Land of the Dead Director's Plans, September - November 2004 (Oversize 67, Folder 8)
        Includes set designs, layouts, effects renderings, and blueprints for numerous sets and scenes.
      - Land of the Dead Director's Plans Tech Survey Day 1 and 2 (copy 1), September 2004 (Oversize 67, Folder 9)
      - Land of the Dead Director's Plans Tech Survey Day 1 and 2 (copy 2), September 2004 (Oversize 67, Folder 10)
      - Land of the Dead extras breakdowns, October 7, 2004 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Land of the Dead shooting schedules, September - December 2004 (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Land of the Dead one liner schedule, September - December 2004 (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Land of the Dead daily hot cost reports, October - November, 2004 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Land of the Dead budgets running tally, September - December 2004 (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Land of the Dead budget topsheets, September - December 2004 (Box 64, Folder 6)
      - Land of the Dead budget cheque requests, August - October 2004 (Box 64, Folder 7)
      - Land of the Dead budget cheque requests, November - December 2004 (Box 64, Folder 8)
      - Land of the Dead budget purchase orders, October - December 2004 (Box 64, Folder 9)
        From budget binder belonging to executive producer Dennis Jones.
      - Land of the Dead cost reports, October 2004 - June 2005 (Box 64, Folder 10)
      - Land of the Dead story boards sections 1-8, September - October 2004 (Box 64, Folder 11)
        Story boards from binder belonging to executive producer Dennis Jones. Contains 8 scenes/sections dated between September 20 and October 27. Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards, September 27, 2004 (Box 64, Folder 12)
        Storyboards sent to executive producer Dennis Jones for scenes "Big Daddy goes in the water" "Zombies come out of the water" and "Zombies come around the corner". Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards, October 2004 (Box 64, Folder 13)
        Story boards sent to executive producter Peter Grunwald for various scenes created thoughout October. Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards, November 2004 (Box 65, Folder 1)
        Story boards sent to executive producer Peter Grunwald for various scenes created throughout November. Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards, November 2, 2004 (Box 65, Folder 2)
        Storyboards sent to executive producer Dennis Jones for scenes 37, 58-68, and 78. Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards, November 24, 2004 (Box 65, Folder 3)
        Story boards sent to executive producer Dennis Jones for various scenes related to "The Throat". Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards, November 27, 2004 (Box 65, Folder 4)
        Story boards sent to executive producer Dennis Jones for "Ghetto chaos sequences". Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards part 1 (copy 1), 2004 (Box 65, Folder 5)
        Story boards from production binder belonging to executive producer Peter Grunwald. Various, non-sequential scenes. Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards part 1 (copy 2), 2004 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - Land of the Dead story boards part 2 (copy 1), 2004 (Box 65, Folder 7)
      - Land of the Dead story boards part 2 (copy 2), 2004 (Box 65, Folder 8)
      - Land of the Dead story boards, 2004 (Box 65, Folder 9)
        Story boards from production binder belonging to executive producer Peter Grunwald. Contains scenes 87a, 166, and 199. Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards sections 1-3, 2004 (Box 65, Folder 10)
        Story boards from binder belonging to executive producer Dennis Jones containing 15 scenes/segments. Folder includes sections 1-3 titled "Bridge", "Garage", and "Ghetto (No. 9 and the gun)". Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards sections 4-6, 2004 (Box 66, Folder 1)
        Story boards from binder belonging to executive producer Dennis Jones containing 15 scenes/segments. Folder includes sections 4-6 titled "Mouse Croaks (Before shed)", "Uniontown", and "Cholo Bitten". Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards sections 7-9, 2004 (Box 66, Folder 2)
        Story boards from binder belonging to executive producer Dennis Jones containing 15 scenes/segments. Folder includes sections 7-9 titled "Ghetto Chaos - Hammertime", "High Angle Ghetto", and "Mouse is Lunch (After shed)". Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards sections 10-12, 2004 (Box 66, Folder 3)
        Story boards from binder belonging to executive producer Dennis Jones containing 15 scenes/segments. Folder includes sections 10-12 titled "Waterfront", "Depot", and "Ghetto Chaos". Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead story boards sections 13-15, 2004 (Box 66, Folder 4)
        Story boards from binder belonging to executive producer Dennis Jones containing 15 scenes/segments. Folder includes sections 13-15 titled "Hillside", "Throat", and "Sc 87A". Drawings by Rob McCallum.
      - Land of the Dead additional units budget, November 3, 2004 (Box 66, Folder 5)
      - Land of the Dead post schedules, 2004-2005 (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - Image still of zombie army with reference art, 2005 (Box 66, Folder 7)
        Printed image still of zombie army from Land of the Dead emerging from the river with reference artwork of similar arrangement of humans walking.
      - Land of the Dead script notes, rewrites, additions, and memos about production, March 2005 (Box 66, Folder 8)
        Various script and scene segments with commentary, suggested rewrites and reshooot notes, and prose reflections on the production of Land of the Dead focusing on issues with special effects, editing and creative decisions on various scenes, and post-production. Includes addtional scenes to be added before scenes 21,41, and 56; original scene 87A script; reshoot and rewrites for March 31 screening; sound notes; short memo and coda; and a long memo.
      - Land of the Dead reshoots outline, story boards, and notes, March 30-31, 2005 (Box 66, Folder 9)
        From binder containing memo with budget for specific scenes and story boards for reshoots. Annotations and notes throughout with focus on special effects.
      - Land of the Dead reshoots story boards and notes, 2005 (Box 66, Folder 10)
        Story boards with notes and annotations throughout for reshoots with focus on special effects.
      - Land of the Dead reshoots budget, April 22, 2005 (Box 66, Folder 11)
      - Land of the Dead reshoots call sheet and schedule, April 2005 (Box 66, Folder 12)
      - Land of the Dead screening reports, June 22, 2005 (Box 66, Folder 13)
      - Land of the Dead screening reports, June 24, 2005 (Box 66, Folder 14)
      - Land of the Dead opening day reviews, June 24, 2005 (Box 66, Folder 15)
      - Land of the Dead graphic novel artwork and notes, 2005-2006 (Box 66, Folder 16)
        Artwork panels with revision notes and correspondence for the 2006 graphic novel version of Land of the Dead adapted by Chris Ryall with art by Gabriel Rodriguez.
    - Diary of the Dead, 2006; 22.
      - Diary of the Dead production documents, September - November 2006 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Diary of the Dead technical survey and set layouts and design sketches, October 2, 2006 (Box 68, Folder 2)
      - Diary of the Dead production wrap-up binder sections 1-6, October - November 2006 (Box 68, Folder 3)
        Production wrap binder belonging to producer Peter Grunwald. Includes sections marked: Items pending at wrap memo, final crew list, final cast list, final contact list, call sheets, daily production reports.
      - Diary of the Dead production wrap-up binder sections 7-9, October - November 2006 (Box 68, Folder 4)
        Production wrap binder belonging to producer Peter Grunwald. Includes sections marked: ACTRA Contrats, Final one line schedule, final day out of days.
      - Diary of the Dead production wrap-up binder sections 10-14, September - October 2006 (Box 68, Folder 5)
        Production wrap binder belonging to producer Peter Grunwald. Includes sections marked: Clearance Reports, Travel Orders, Immigration Work Authorization Letters, Location Agreements, Insurance Certificates.
    - Survival of the Dead [Blank of the Dead], 2008; 23.
      - Blank of the Dead set design diagrams and scene notes, 2008 (Box 68, Folder 7)
      - Blank of the Dead wrap binder part 1, September - November 2008 (Box 68, Folder 8)
      - Blank of the Dead wrap binder part 2, September - November 2008 (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Blank of the Dead wrap binder part 3, September - November 2008 (Box 69, Folder 2)
        Production wrap binder belonging to executive producer Peter Grunwald. Includes sections marked: Insurance, Acccident Reports, Union Variances.
      - Blank of the Dead production materials [REMOVE], 2008 (Box 66, Folder 5)
        Includes: location agreements, insurance, accident reports, union variances.
      - Blank of the Dead wrap binder part 4, November 2008 (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Blank of the Dead day 2 shooting schedule, call sheet, and maps to set, September 29, 2008 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - The Crazies [2010], August 18, 2005; 24.
      A remake of the film written and directed by George A. Romero, in which a virus causes the population to grow violent and uninhibited. Starring Timothy Olyphant and Radha Mitchell. Written by Scott Kosar and Ray Wright. Directed by Breck Eisner.
      - Contract for The Crazies remake, August 18, 2005 (Box 69, Folder 5)